gooddata.com 2019-07-01

# Privacy Policy | GoodData

This Privacy Policy applies to [gooddata.com](https://www.gooddata.com/) which is owned and operated by GoodData Corporation (“ **GoodData** ", “ **We** ”, “ **Us** ” or “ **Our** ”). GoodData is committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information.

This Privacy Policy describes how GoodData collects, uses, shares and secures the personal information you provide Us. This Privacy Policy applies to data collected by GoodData Corporation and its subsidiaries through the gooddata.com Web site, other web pages that we operate in which we post a direct link to this Privacy Policy, and the GoodData Platform (each a " **GoodData Site** "). It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your personal information. By voluntarily using a GoodData Site and/or providing data or other information by or through a GoodData Site, you (on behalf of yourself and/or the legal entity that you represent) are indicating your consent to this Privacy Policy and agree, on behalf of yourself and/or the legal entity that you represent) to be bound by its terms.

## Personal Information We Collect From You

### Personal Data You May Choose to Provide to GoodData

You can visit a GoodData Site without telling us who you are and without actively revealing any personal information about yourself except for certain personal information which may be collected as a result of your visit to the Site (e.g. your “digital fingerprint”, see the next section for more information). There are times, however, when We may need certain personal information from you.

You may choose to provide us with personal information (such as your name, email address, phone number, business contact information, and billing information) through a GoodData Site when you elect to register with GoodData in order to download or access our products or services. When you provide Us personal information in order to register with GoodData, such personal information will be used in order to provide you with access to the requested products, services content and/or information, or for the purpose of providing you with professional services and/or support, as necessary under a contractual agreement. We may also use the personal information to help us understand who is using our products and services and to help us manage business development activities. GoodData may also use personal information for marketing purposes. For example, GoodData may use information you provide to contact you to further discuss your interest in our products or services and to send you information regarding GoodData and its partners, such as information about promotions or events. If you tell Us that you do not want Us to use this personal information as a basis for further contact with you, We will respect your wishes. Please contact us at [**privacy@gooddata.com**](mailto:privacy@gooddata.com).

### Personal Information that are Collected Passively

As is true of most websites, GoodData gathers certain information automatically and stores this data in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (“ **IP** ”) addresses, browser type, the identity of your internet service provider (“ **ISP** ”), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data.

### Information Related to Data Collected for our Customers

In the case of individuals using the GoodData Platform, GoodData collects information under the direction of Our business clients (“ **Customers** ”) acting on your behalf and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal information it processes. GoodData works with its Customers to help them provide notice to their customers and end users concerning the purposes for which personal information is collected. The use of personal information collected through the GoodData Platform shall be limited to the purpose of providing the products or service for which you have engaged GoodData.

## How We Use Personal Information We Collect from You

### Newsletters

If you wish to subscribe to Our newsletter, We will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, We provide you with a way to unsubscribe. Please see the " **Choice/Opt-out** " section of this Privacy Policy.

### Improvement of our Services

When you visit a GoodData Site, GoodData collects your IP addresses to track and aggregate pseudonymized information. For example, GoodData uses IP addresses to monitor the regions from which customers and visitors navigate to a GoodData Site, which features they use etc.

GoodData and our online marketing partners (including certain advertising and sales generation service providers) use technologies such as cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about Our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual or aggregated basis.

We may combine the passively collected information described in the previous section with other information We collect about you. We do this to improve services We offer you (including the product experience), and to improve overall marketing, analytics, and site functionality.

### Usage of GoodData Platform

If you are end user customer of GoodData Platform, We use your personal information to provide you with an identity on the GoodData Platform. Your personal information may be made available to other end users from within your organization with whom you collaborate within the GoodData Platform and to relevant GoodData personnel responsible for support and Platform operations.

### Authentication and Personalization

We use cookies to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference), for authentication on the GoodData Platform applications and to provide relevant information on our public websites. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our website may be limited.

### Behavioral Targeting and Re-Targeting

We partner with a third party advertising partner, or “ad network”, to either display advertising on the GoodData Site(s) or to manage Our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and similar technologies to collect pseudonymized information about your activities on the GoodData Site and other Web sites to provide you with targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you do not wish to have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted advertisements, you may opt out by clicking here ([ **http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/**](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/)). Please note this selection does not opt you out of being served advertising altogether. You will continue to receive generic advertisements. If you are located in the European Union, click here: [**http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/**](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)

We use Google AdSense to publish advertisements on select GoodData Sites. When you view or click on an advertisement, a cookie will be set to help better provide advertisements that may be of interest to you on this and other GoodData Sites. You may opt-out of the use of this Google AdSense cookie by visiting Google’s Privacy & Terms page for Advertising: [**http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html**](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

### Security

As part of GoodData's general security features, GoodData also collects IP addresses from end user customers and sets certain cookies when a customer logs into the GoodData Platform.

### Links to Other Web Sites

A GoodData Site may contain links to other web sites. GoodData is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such third party web sites. The links from a GoodData Site do not imply that GoodData endorses or has reviewed the third party web sites. We suggest contacting the operators of those web sites directly for information regarding their privacy policies.

### Project Invitations

If you choose to invite others within your organization to a report or workspace on a GoodData Site, We will ask you for the other user's name and email address. We will automatically send him/her a one-time email inviting him/her to visit a GoodData Site. GoodData stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. Invited users may contact us at [**privacy@gooddata.com**](mailto:privacy@gooddata.com) to request that We remove this contact information from our database.

### Adding a Participant to Register for Training/Purchasing a Catalog for Someone Else

If you choose to purchase a catalog for someone else or add a participant to register for a GoodData training session, We will ask you for that person’s name, email, company name, job title and phone number. We will automatically send him/her a one-time email inviting him/her to register. GoodData stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking success of the registration. Invited users may contact us at [**privacy@gooddata.com**](mailto:privacy@gooddata.com) to request that We remove this contact information from our database.

### Blogs/Forums/Chat Rooms/Bulletin Boards

If you use a blog, forum, chat room or bulletin board on a GoodData Site (" **Forum(s)** "), you should be aware that any personal information you submit in a Forum can be read, collected, or used by other users of such Forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in a Forum. To request removal of your personal information from our Forums, contact us at [**privacy@gooddata.com**](mailto:privacy@gooddata.com). In some cases, We may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case We will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

### Customer Testimonials

GoodData may post customer testimonials on a GoodData Site, which may contain personal information. We obtain our customers’ consent prior to posting their testimonials. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, contact us at [**privacy@gooddata.com**](mailto:privacy@gooddata.com).

### Social Media Widgets

GoodData Sites include social media features, such as the Facebook “Like” button and widgets, such as the “Share This” button or interactive mini-programs that run on a GoodData Site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on a GoodData Site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on the applicable GoodData Site. Your interactions with each third party feature are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the social media feature and widgets.

### Customer Relationship

If you are a GoodData customer or you are working with GoodData sales personnel on a possible engagement between GoodData and your company, We may use your personal information you provided to Us, particularly your business contact information and information relevant for the engagement, for the purpose of managing the relationship and in connection with any potential contractual arrangements between our companies.

### Support and Professional Services

If you are a GoodData customer or end-user of the GoodData Platform, We may be processing your personal information as a part of a professional services engagement and/or in order to provide You with our technical support services. The information collected for this purpose will include your contact information and all information relevant to the particular services engagement and/or to the issue that is being addressed by our support organization.

## Choice

If you are a customer end user using the GoodData Platform and would no longer like to have your personal information used by GoodData or our customer, please contact that customer directly. If you seek access to personal information, or seek to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate personal information or other data, collected by GoodData under the direction of our customer, please direct your query to the customer (e.g. the entity that is the data controller). If the customer requests GoodData to remove the personal information or other data, We will respond to our customer request within 30 days.

## Service Providers and Onward Transfer

GoodData may transfer personal information that We collect under the direction of our Customers to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to these third parties are covered by the provisions in this Privacy Policy and in the service agreements We have with our Customers. All transfer of personal information to these third parties is subject to all  applicable data protection laws and regulations, and, whenever required, subject to the specific contractual arrangements between Us and the third party. GoodData regularly verifies compliance of its service providers to applicable laws and regulations.

## Our Disclosure of Your Personal Information and Other Information

GoodData is not in the business of selling your personal information. We consider this information to be a vital part of Our relationship with you. There are, however, certain circumstances in which We may share your personal information with certain third parties, as set forth below:

  * Related Companies: We may share your information with affiliated business partners, for instance, for the purpose of enhancing Our products and services or so that they can market their products or services to you. If you do not want Us to share your personal information with these companies, contact us at [**privacy@gooddata.com**](mailto:privacy@gooddata.com).
  * Agents, Consultants and Related Third Parties: GoodData, like many businesses, sometimes hires other companies to perform certain business-related functions. Examples of such functions include mailing information, maintaining databases and processing payments. When We employ another company to perform a function of this nature, We only provide it with the information that it needs to perform its specific function.
  * Legal Notice: In certain situations, GoodData may be required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or other legal demand, when We believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect Our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request. If GoodData is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or by way a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership, uses of your personal information, and choices you may have regarding your personal information. We may also disclose your personal information to any other third party with your prior consent.  

## Joint Offerings

From time to time, GoodData may partner with other companies to jointly offer products or services. If you purchase or specifically express interest in a jointly offered product or service from us, GoodData may share certain information collected in connection with your purchase or expression of interest with our joint promotion partner(s). GoodData does not control our business partners' use of the information We share with them, and their use of the information will be in accordance with their own privacy policies. If you do not wish for your information to be shared in connection with any joint offerings, you may opt not to purchase or specifically express interest in a jointly offered product or service.

## International Transfer of Information Collected

To facilitate GoodData's global operations, GoodData may transfer and access information regarding GoodData customers from around the world, including the United States. This Privacy Policy shall apply even if GoodData transfers information regarding GoodData Customers, end users or GoodData Site users to other countries.

## Customer Data

GoodData Customers and its end users may electronically submit data or information to the GoodData Platform for hosting and processing purposes (" **Customer Data** "). GoodData will not review, share, distribute, or reference any such Customer Data except as provided in the GoodData Terms of Use (see: [**https://www.gooddata.com/terms-of-use/current**](https://www.gooddata.com/terms-of-use/current)), in individual Customer service agreements, or as may be required by law. In accordance with the GoodData Terms of Use, GoodData may access Customer Data only for the purpose of providing the GoodData services, preventing or addressing service or technical problems, at a GoodData customer's request in connection with customer support matters, or as may be required by law.

## Security

All personal information collected by GoodData is maintained in a secure manner, and all reasonable precautions are taken to secure this personal information. However, no email transmission or data storage is ever fully secure or error free. In particular, email sent to or from a GoodData Site may not be secure. Therefore, you should take special care in deciding what information you send to GoodData via email. Please keep this security limitation in mind when disclosing any personal information to GoodData through the Internet. The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information on our registration pages or order forms, We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received. Please refer to [**https://www.gooddata.com/security**](https://www.gooddata.com/security) for additional information about the information security standards and best practices we have implemented. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [**privacy@gooddata.com**](mailto:privacy@gooddata.com).

## Schedule Notices and Alert Emails

Based on written selections you make once you initiate use of the GoodData Platform, you may receive schedule email notices generated by the GoodData Platform (such as dashboards, reports or key performance indicators) or related to Platform operations (e.g. including maintenance announcements) and special alert email communications describing Platform system status. If you no longer wish to receive our scheduled Platform notifications or special alert emails, you may unsubscribe at any time by using the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of such communication or by sending us an email at [**privacy@gooddata.com**](mailto:privacy@gooddata.com).

## Choice/Opt-out

If you no longer wish to receive our emails, newsletters or other communications, you may unsubscribe at any time by using the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of such communication or by sending us an email at [ **privacy@gooddata.com**](mailto:privacy@gooddata.com).

## Correcting, Updating and Accessing Your Personal Information

Upon request GoodData will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. To request this information please contact us at [**privacy@gooddata.com**](mailto:privacy@gooddata.com). You will have the right to contact us to request information about the personal information we have collected from you and to request the correction, modification or deletion of such personal information. To make such a request and/or to pose any other questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact GoodData via email at [**privacy@gooddata.com**](mailto:privacy@gooddata.com). You may also correct, modify or delete your registration information by logging into your GoodData account and going to the account settings page. Requests made to GoodData to access, change or delete personal information will be addressed within 30 days. We will retain your personal information We collect from you and that We process on behalf of our Customers for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you products or services. We will retain and use your personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Region or Locality Specific Privacy Rights

### EU Privacy Rights

GoodData and its subsidiary GoodData s.r.o. are committed to fully comply with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR** ”). If your personal data (as defined in GDPR) that is being processed by GoodData are subject to GDPR, you are entitled to certain privacy rights, which are listed and explained below. If you wish to exercise any of these privacy rights under GDPR or if you need further information regarding those privacy rights, please contact us at privacy@goodata.com.

Note that certain processing rights might be undertaken by GoodData and its subsidiaries only in those scenarios in which GoodData is a data controller. This set of processing rights excludes all situations in which GoodData processes Personal Data of GoodData customers and/or the customers’ clients on or through the GoodData Platform, where GoodData is a processor and not a controller.

  1. Right of confirmation
  2. Right of access
  3. Right to rectification
  4. Right to erasure (Right to be forgotten)
  5. Right of restriction of processing
  6. Right to data portability
  7. Right to object
  8. Automated individual decision-making, including profiling  

### EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield

GoodData and its subsidiary GoodData s.r.o. participate in and has certified its compliance with, the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively (“ **Privacy Shield Framework** ”). GoodData and its subsidiary GoodData s.r.o. have certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [**https://www.privacyshield.gov/**](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

GoodData is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. GoodData complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal information from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal information received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, GoodData is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, GoodData may be required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact the GoodData Privacy Administrator at: privacy@gooddata.com. If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry, or if your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [**https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request**](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [**https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint**](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

### California Privacy Rights

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your personal information by GoodData to its affiliates and/or third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email with your first name, last name, mailing address, email address, and telephone number to GoodData at the address below. Please include “California Privacy Rights” in the subject line of your email.

## Changes to Our Policy

We may change our business and any GoodData Site from time to time. As a result, at times it may be necessary for us to make changes to this Privacy Policy. GoodData reserves the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time without prior notice. If We make material changes to this Privacy Policy, We will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices, and especially before you provide GoodData with any personal information. This Privacy Policy was last updated on the date indicated at the top of this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of a GoodData Site after any changes or revisions to this Privacy Policy have been published shall indicate your agreement with the terms of such revised Privacy Policy.

## Contact Us

Personal Data are collected by:

GoodData Corporation  
660 Third Street, Suite 101  
San Francisco, California 94107, U.S.A.  

and/or its subsidiary:

GoodData s.r.o.   
Moravské nám. 1007/14, 602 00 Brno-střed-Veveří  
Czech Republic, EU.
